export const GENERALKNOWLEDGEINARTSA2020 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. One reason for studying visual art is to",
A: "become civilized.",
B: "enable one fight injustice.",
C: "foster creativity.",
D: "learn to become patriotic.",
answer: "C. foster creativity.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The Indian figure Lord of the Dance was executed in",
A: "bronze.",
B: "cement.",
C: "granite.",
D: "wood.",
answer: "C. granite.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Non-representational art is also known as",
A: "abstract art.",
B: "naturalistic art.",
C: "realistic art.",
D: "romantic art.",
answer: "A. abstract art.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The original Discus Thrower by Myron was",
A: "bronze.",
B: "iron.",
C: "marble.",
D: "quartz.",
answer: "A. bronze.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Claude Monet is associated with",
A: "Cubism.",
B: "Expressionism.",
C: "Fauvism.",
D: "Impressionism",
answer: "D. Impressionism",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Which of these is true of art appreciation?",
A: "Good works are designed",
B: "Mistakes in art work are criticized",
C: "Work of art is discussed without judging it",
D: "Work of art is explained and judged",
answer: "C. Work of art is discussed without judging it",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The human head in most African sculpture is exaggerated because",
A: "the carvers have no formal training.",
B: "the carvers love big leads.",
C: "it is carved to meet the demand of clients.",
D: "it is considered to be the seat of power.",
answer: "D. it is considered to be the seat of power.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The concept of art which deals with the appreciation of beauty is referred to as",
A: "aesthetics.",
B: "criticism.",
C: "perception.",
D: "perspective",
answer: "A. aesthetics.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following textures is visual?",
A: "Bark of trees",
B: "Cardboard",
C: "Photography",
D: "Wall surface",
answer: "C. Photography",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. A resourceful artist",
A: "appreciates his national and cultural heritage.",
B: "relies on foreign tools and materials for his work.",
C: "understands and applies scientific knowledge.",
D: "uses tools and materials from his environment",
answer: "D. uses tools and materials from his environment",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. To perceive with kinaesthetic sense is to",
A: "feel the weight of an object.",
B: "imagine the real size of an object.",
C: "smell a scent.",
D: "taste the flavour of food.",
answer: "A. feel the weight of an object.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Perception is a process of",
A: "creating",
B: "criticising.",
C: "drawing.",
D: "Thinking.",
answer: "D. Thinking.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The area labelled A is the",
A: "end paper.",
B: "fore-edge.",
C: "head.",
D: "spine",
answer: "C. head",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. What is the name of the area labeled B?",
A: "End paper",
B: "Fore-edge",
C: "Head",
D: "Spine",
answer: "B. Fore-edge",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The name of the area marked C is the",
A: "end paper.",
B: "fore-edge.",
C: "head.",
D: "spine.",
answer: "D. spine",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Ancient Greek and African arts are similar because they",
A: "dwelt on spherical shapes.",
B: "immortalized the dead.",
C: "practised abstraction.",
D: "projected the human figure.",
answer: "B. immortalized the dead.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. A caveman’s media for artistic expression comprised",
A: "earth colours, charcoal and stones.",
B: "oil colours, polish and metals.",
C: "plasticine, wax and acrylics.",
D: "plastics, pastel and rubber.",
answer: "A. earth colours, charcoal and stones.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The repetition of elements to provide progressive and related movement is termed",
A: "dominance.",
B: "opposition.",
C: "rhythm.",
D: "unity",
answer: "C. rhythm.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. To change a yellow cloth into green colour, it should be dyed in",
A: "black.",
B: "blue.",
C: "purple.",
D: "red.",
answer: "B. blue.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which group of letters comprises a combination of only strokes and lobes?",
A: "BDPR",
B: "EIMX",
C: "COSU",
D: "RCJK",
answer: "C. COSU",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. In a Ghanaian society, triangle symbolizes",
A: "Beauty",
B: "Femininity",
C: "Fertility",
D: "security",
answer: "D. security",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which paper is ideal for charcoal drawing?",
A: "Bond paper",
B: "Ingress",
C: "Newsprint",
D: "Sugar paper",
answer: "B. Ingress",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Gold is used at outdooring mainly to signify",
A: "continuous life.",
B: "prosperity of the state.",
C: "purity.",
D: "rule of king.",
answer: "C. purity.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Kyenkyen and Tapa are produced from",
A: "leather.",
B: "rubber.",
C: "silk cotton.",
D: "tree bark.",
answer: "C. silk cotton.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The canoe symbol of star signifies",
A: "hope.",
B: "light.",
C: "protection.",
D: "stability.",
answer: "A. hope.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The most important aspect of a traditional carving is its",
A: "beauty.",
B: "meaning.",
C: "size.",
D: "smoothness.",
answer: "B. meaning.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. At puberty, white is mainly used to signify",
A: "love and tenderness.",
B: "newness and fertility.",
C: "purity and virginity.",
D: "vitality and growth.",
answer: "C. purity and virginity.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which of the following is an indigenous African communal object?",
A: "Domestic stool",
B: "Mask",
C: "Mortar",
D: "Wooden comb",
answer: "C. Mortar",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The tool for transferring hot wax in batik design is called",
A: "pliers.",
B: "rollers.",
C: "squeegee.",
D: "tjanting.",
answer: "D. tjanting.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The acid used to etch a design on a metal plate is referred to as",
A: "agent.",
B: "material",
C: "substance",
D: "tool",
answer: "A. agent.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Pyrography refers to",
A: "engraving on metals.",
B: "etched design on metal.",
C: "incised contours on wood",
D: "scorched designs on wood",
answer: "D. scorched designs on wood",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. A heavy application of paint onto canvas is called",
A: "Chiaroscuro",
B: "Impasto",
C: "Sfumato",
D: "stippling",
answer: "B. Impasto",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following statements best defines a ferrule?",
A: "A hollow container for reproducing forms",
B: "An article made from wood",
C: "The metal part of an artist’s brush",
D: "The wooden par1 of a brush",
answer: "C. The metal part of an artist’s brush",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The largest number of rock engravings and paintings are located in",
A: "Kenya.",
B: "Kilimanjaro.",
C: "Tassili.",
D: "Uganda.",
answer: "C. Tassili.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. An all-over pattern begins with",
A: "counter change.",
B: "full drop.",
C: "motif.",
D: "ogee.",
answer: "C. motif.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Animism involves belief in",
A: "ancestral veneration.",
B: "life after death.",
C: "spirits.",
D: "witchcraft.",
answer: "C. spirits.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. In making direct prints, ideas are collected from",
A: "books.",
B: "screens.",
C: "stencils.",
D: "surfaces.",
answer: "D. surfaces.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Directional information is usually found on",
A: "banners.",
B: "billboards.",
C: "signboards.",
D: "signposts.",
answer: "C. signboards.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Processed material which is meaningful to the user in computing is called",
A: "data.",
B: "file.",
C: "information.",
D: "record.",
answer: "C. information.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. A surface that is made to appear tactile is referred to as",
A: "actual texture.",
B: "coarse texture.",
C: "simulated texture.",
D: "smooth texture",
answer: "C. simulated texture.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]